Antoine Bolvy

I am looking for a company that has environmental and social impact. After several years as a Lead Developer in startups and several freelance missions, I have acquired strong expertise and autonomy.

With 7 years of experience in Fullstack JS (Node/React/MongoDB/PostgreSQL), I am very open to another stack because I enjoy discovering new technologies and staying at the forefront.

+33675455349 antoine.bolvy@gmail.com Paris, France

Last updated: 2nd March 2023

LINKS

Github /saveman71
Linkedin /in/antoinebolvy
Twitter @saveman71
Facebook /saveman71

Website https://saveman71.com

SKILLS HIGHLIGHT

PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT

- Developed products from scratch
- Able to manage a small team
- Product-oriented mindset
- Great autonomy and communication skills, transparency advocate
- Sharing is caring (have a look at my website!)

OTHER

- Writing multilingual documentation with LATEX and Markdown (this resume is actually written in LATEX)
- Actively engaged in Open-Source works and communities
- Curious!

LANGUAGES

English: Full professional proficiency

French: Native

EDUCATION

EPITECH

Master in Computer Science Valedictorian

2013 - 2018 | Paris, France

CONCORDIA UNIVERSITY

VISITING STUDENT IN COMPUTER SCIENCES, GRADUATE LEVEL

2016 - 2017 | Montréal, Canada

HOBBIES

COOKING

I love cooking and making complex dishes. I am also a vegetarian.

ESPRESSO

I enjoy discovering new flavors and taking care of my coffee machines.

3D PRINTING

Spare parts, decorative objects, upgrades for my coffee machine;)

PLANTS

Anything that grows, I love it!

EXPERIENCE

Freelance | Senior Full-Stack Software Engineer

2015 - Present | Remote

Node.js TypeScript PostgreSQL React Python AWS Terraform

- Missions from several days to several months
- Various clients: startups, SMEs and large groups
- Varied demand: small needs (scripts), development of applications alone or in tandem with a front-end dev and management of deployments on AWS with Terraform
- Worked with multiple clients on tight schedules

La Belle Assiette | Lead Senior Software Engineer

Sept 2017 - June 2022 (5 years) | Paris, France

Node.js MongoDB/mongoose React AngularJS AWS Terraform

La Belle Assiette brings talented chefs into your kitchen so you can enjoy hosting dinners without the stress of cooking or cleaning. Website

- Managed the engineering team
- Implemented new features for the on-line booking platform, the chef's back-office and the admin back-office
- Maintained and performed critical upgrades (MongoDB, AWS, etc.), implemented best practices in the team

Kids-OK | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug 2015 - Jul 2016 | Lyon, France

Node.js MongoDB/mongoose AngularJS Android/Java

Kids-OK was a Lyon-based startup that wanted to offer parents solutions to protect their kids on new technology and social networks. Website (archived)

- Designed and maintained the back-end API (interacting with social APIs: Facebook, Twitter, Instagram), set up CI and automated tests, prototyped a natural language processing algorithm to detect swear words
- Developed an advanced Android application: a secure launcher for children
- Gained experience in project management, took leadership on the product, made design decisions

AnyFetch | Software Engineer (Internship)

Jul 2014 - Mar 2015 | Lyon, France

Node.js MongoDB/mongoose Chrome extension

AnyFetch was a startup aiming to provide people with a cloud-wide document search, integrating with popular services such as Gmail, Dropbox, etc. Website (archived), Product Hunt post

- Developed a Google Chrome Extension in JavaScript. Screenshots
- Maintained the large-scale REST API (150+ calls per second) written in Node.js, several micro-services, and the client-side management interface

PROJECTS

KISS Launcher | Contributor and co-maintainer

Jan 2015 - Present

KISS Launcher is a blazingly fast open-source launcher for Android. Website